Ron Yih-Lun Huang

ron@hng.tw | https://ron.hng.tw/ | +886-920033167

Summary

Seasoned developer with usability and user experience in mind. Led and participated various projects and international competitions. Demonstrated talent for analyzing problems and finding innovative solutions. Familiar with human-computer interaction, various programming languages and web standards. Highly motivated, always staying connected with the latest trends in leading technologies.

Experience

Software Engineer

June 2013 - Now

Hewlett Packard Enterprise, Taipei, Taiwan Hewlett-Packard Company, Taipei, Taiwan

- Architected web service for test automation used across test teams within HP.
- Designed various DevOps processes, such as repeatable development environment with Vagrant and Puppet, continuous integration pipeline with Jenkins, release management with Git and Maven, network monitoring with Nagios, etc.
- Integrated web service with an internal Linux platform, which involves package creation and signature process, installation/upgrade procedure, high-availability cluster management, backup/restore mechanism, authentication/authorization, indexing and searching capability, etc.
- $\bullet\,$ Developed test tool for server virtualization, including Microsoft Hyper-V and VMware vSphere.

Staff Engineer

October 2011 - December 2012

Generalplus Technology Inc., Taipei, Taiwan

- Ported Android operating system (hardware abstraction layer and above) onto custom designed ARM system-on-a-chip solution.
- Implemented new features and enhanced build system to support sophisticated customization requirements from customers.
- Refactored existing porting implementation to comply with Android standards and idioms. Greatly reduced porting time frame between major Android releases.
- Maintained and synchronized internal repositories with Android upstream.

Ph.D. Student

July 2009 - June 2011

National University of Singapore, Singapore

• Worked on Software Patterns of User Experience, a collection of the best practices within the user experience design domain. But instead of targeting end-users and designers, these patterns are transcribed in language familiar to developers.

Advanced Software Engineer

December 2007 - June 2009

Sunplus mMedia Inc., Taipei, Taiwan

• Developed a complete software development kit for digital photo frame.

Software Engineer

February 2005 - December 2007

Compal Communications Inc., Taipei, Taiwan

- Ported various in-house and off-the-shelf GUI frameworks onto feature phones.
- Developed a C-based object-oriented GUI framework, including code generator and automated test framework for feature phone.
- Optimized display performance for GUI framework.

Education

M.S. Computer Science

December 2004

University of Southern California, Los Angeles, California, USA Major GPA: 3.95, Area of study: Human-Computer Interaction

B.S. Electrical Engineering

June 2002

National Taiwan University, Taipei, Taiwan

Major GPA: 3.73

Skills Programming

Python, C, Lua, JavaScript, C++, Shell scripting, Go, SQL

Language:

Tools: Emacs, Git, Subversion, Regular expression, Maven, Vagrant,

Puppet, Jenkins, Ansible, Docker, Makefile, HTML, CSS

Awards

NUS Research Scholarship

July 2009

National University of Singapore

Honorable Mention

June 2006

Google Desktop Gadget Contest, Google

First Place June 2003

4th Annual Computer Society International Design Competition, IEEE

Fifth Place June 2001

2nd Annual Computer Society International Design Competition, IEEE

Publications

Software Patterns of User Experience: Giving Software Developers More Say in the Design Process

Jun 2011

5th Conference on Designing Pleasurable Products and Interfaces, Milan, Italy Yih-Lun Huang and Tim Marsh

Investigation of Software Patterns of User Experience November 2010 7th Conference on Advances in Computer Entertainment Technology, Taipei, Taiwan Yih-Lun Huang, Tim Marsh and Adrian David Cheok

User Experiences and Lessons Learned from Developing and Implementing an Immersive Game for the Science Classroom

July 2005

Proceedings of HCI International 2005, Las Vegas, Nevada, USA

Marsh, Tim, Wee Ling Wong, Eduardo Carriazo, Luciano Nocera, Kiyoung Yang, Aditiya Varma, Hyunjin Yoon, Y. L. Huang, Chris Kyriakakis and Cyrus Shahabi

Projects (Selected)

Where is Makkah \to http://github.com/ronhuang/where-is-makkah July 2011 C^{\sharp} , XAML

• Windows Phone 7 app that shows the direction to Makkah (Mecca.)

 $\begin{array}{l} \textbf{Vistroller} \rightarrow \texttt{http://github.com/ronhuang/vistroller} \\ \textbf{C}, \ Java, \ \textbf{C++} \end{array}$

May 2011

- Arduino shield that captures inputs from PS2 controller and renders augmented reality markers onto the connected LCD panel in real-time.
- Android library that translates captured markers (from Camera) into key events.
- Game can easily incorporate Vistroller and play through PS2 controller.

Last updated: March 23, 2016